Wandile Nyembe

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Portfolio Website

https://wandilenyembe.netlify.app

CONTACT

0728026231

Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/wandilenyembe-a69bb31b8/

OBJECTIVE

I am a 3rd Year Computer Engineering and Computer Science UCT student. I am looking to apply my 2 years of experience, not only as a Computer Science Undergraduate student, but also as a Software Engineer intern, to help with Front end Web development (HTML, JavaScript, CSS).

EDUCATION -

Paul Pietersburg Primary School, KZN.

- School choir member.
- Played rugby, U12 Bteam

Domino Servite Private School

- Played Soccer, U19 Ateam
- Selected as Prefect
- Matriculated with 3 distinctions

University Of Cape Town

- BSc in Computer Science and Computer Engineering (2020 – 2023)

EXPERIENCE

March 2021 - June 2021

Computer Science Tutor • UCT

I tutored a Computer Science course, CSC1015F, which is an introductory course to Python for first years.

August 2021 - November 2021

University House Academic Representative • UCT

My responsibility was ensuring that the fellow students had access to resources that could boost their Academic performance.

Dec 2021 - Jan 2022

Software Engineer Virtual Intern • JP Morgan Chase & Co.

I built a web application that displays a graph for traders. The graph gets continuously updated according to the ratio of the ask price to the bid price of the stock. Thus, python was used for the backend server, to send http requests to the graph in the browser. The React framework was used to display the graph.

[Certification available on Linkedin]

KEY SKILLS -

SKILLS AND EXPERTISE

Hackerank Certification [Available on Linkedin]

- Java (Basic)
- C# (basic)

Java Pvthon

Git

HTML

C#.NET

Linux OS

Embedded C

CSS

MySQL

Git Hub

JavaScript

VS Code

REFERENCES

[Available upon request.]